<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bill's Conversational Musings</title><link>http://blog.billhertzing.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.billhertzing.com/feeds/rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><item><title>WordCamp 2015 San Antonio</title><link>http://blog.billhertzing.com/wordcamp-san-antonio.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://blogimages.billhertzing.com/Bill-at-Wordcamp.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past Saturday I worked the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cloudu"&gt;CloudU&lt;/a&gt; booth at San Antonio's &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/WordCampSATX"&gt;WordCamp 2015&lt;/a&gt; in San Antonio.  This is a conference for all things Wordpress.  There were developers, marketers and bloggers in attendance.  People were there to learn more about Wordpress and how they could better use the technology.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordpress is probably the most popular content management system in use today.  According to the stats from the opening keynote, Wordpress powers "over 60% of the top 10 million websites using an available CMS (23% of the top 10 million websites overall)."  Although these conferences had been held in other cities including Austin, this was San Antonio's first for this user group.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I am going write about what I saw at the conference and what I would like to see at future conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Saw&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Passion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you notice is that people were genuinely excited about being there.  At the conference I saw a good deal of passion for the code, deploying the code and how to be better users.  The people there really embrace the software.  I didn't hear one disparaging remark about the code base itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many were seeking how to adapt it more.  Some were running static pages and looking to leverage Wordpress to take their site to the next level.  Others were looking to know more about the tool they were already using. All-in-all they were passionate about getting more from this content management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees were seeking a deeper knowledge on Wordpress usage. First thing to mention is the software.  Many had questions about what's new in Wordpress.  They were sharing stories about plugins, themes and lessons learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, caching and page load times was a hot topic.  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheWPressGuy"&gt;Anthony Burchell&lt;/a&gt; provided more advanced technical knowledge as he shared how to use caching both internally and externally.  From past experiences at similar conferences I have found that topics around faster page load times are always popular.  Anthony is known as the Wordpress guy at Rackspace and a new plug-in he introduced was the &lt;a href="http://wprediscache.com"&gt;caching plugin using Redis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to peek into the &lt;em&gt;Zero to WordPress&lt;/em&gt; talk led by Michele Butcher.  It was a packed room as many were anxious to learn about the basics of Wordpress.  Many that I talked to said they were really looking forward to that talk as they wanted to get in on the ground floor of what running Wordpress was all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://blogimages.billhertzing.com/Garrett-Talk2.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pinojo"&gt;Garrett Heath&lt;/a&gt;'s talk titled &lt;em&gt;Things I’ve Learned from 5+ Years of Blogging&lt;/em&gt; was another event that was standing room only. Garrett shared what he has learned about maintaining &lt;a href="http://www.saflavor.com"&gt;SA Flavor&lt;/a&gt;, his local blog on San Antonio food and culture. He states that, "While WordPress has made it easier than ever for people to get their thoughts out there, aspiring bloggers often start with a lot of gusto and quickly abandon their blogs."  He stressed the importance of writing on a regular basis and the telling stories.  When you do that the audience will continue to come back for more.  Another key take away was that your blog is your resume.  That means when people look at you (or your resume) they will also look up what you have written or contributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the talks I wasn't able to attend, I was able to catch a few tweets.  I saw where the Wordpress troubleshooting talk had some good advice.  Basically, if you are having trouble with your site, it might be best to deactivate all the plug-ins and toggle them one at a time.  This helps isolate the issue.  You can then see if it is something you need and if so, find a replacement plugin.  I know from experience that this is a common issue when Wordpress gets updated and the plugins do not.  Another consideration might be re-installing Wordpress altogether.  However, before you do make sure you have a backup of your site (all Wordpress content) and your database.  These are the two vital pieces to restoring a Wordpress configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Would Like to See&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Discussions around Scaling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scaling a Wordpress site presents its own unique challenges when it comes to caching and administration.  Although it was mentioned briefly in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DrewCoxSa"&gt;Drew Cox&lt;/a&gt;'s talk about conducting your own Wordpress fire drill, scaling a site for appropriate traffic loads is an important consideration.  As traffic increases, your infrastructure needs to grow or adapt as well.  Then as the traffic subsides, resources should be scaled back.  I don't imagine a discussion on this topic would require its own time slot. However, it would be wise to have it included in a talk around important things to know such as load testing, administration and the like.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Redundancy and Availability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no real mention of building a Wordpress configuration that is redundant and highly available.  Most attendees, I gathered after speaking to them, were using a platform as a service or PaaS.  All were concerned about uptime and availability.  Those that were using PaaS, the infrastructure pieces are managed by their providers.  However, for other people running Wordpress on servers, physical or cloud, it's important to have a site that can be or is replicated to other infrastructure.  That way, should something fail, minimal downtime is encountered as a switch over takes place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deploying eCommerce&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, many people who attended WordCamp were there to better their knowledge around building sites where they had things to sell.  It is true that most were there seeking information to run Wordpress as a blog.  However, a good number of people, 30% by my guesstimate, I spoke with were developers who were writing themes for clients to sell their goods and services.  In a quick search I found that there are at least &lt;a href="http://www.wpexplorer.com/20-best-e-commerce-wordpress-plugins-2014/"&gt;twenty different plugins for Wordpress shopping and commerce&lt;/a&gt;.  An initial look at which plugins are commonly used or how to use Wordpress for eCommerce in general, I feel, would be of enormous value for attendees of future Wordcamp events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordcamp 2015 did help many find the answers to what they were seeking.  Whether it is security or a better way to educate their staff for updates to come, any knowledge was greatly appreciated.  It's clear that Wordpress is moving ahead at a rapid pace.  The Wordpress community I saw was a vibrant, helpful bunch.  They are dedicated professionals on a mission to tell a great story.  If code is poetry as is says on the Wordpress website, then these individuals are true artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have a comment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think? Did I miss anything?  Is any part unclear?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BillHertzing"&gt;Send me a message on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Hertzing</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.billhertzing.com,2015-01-26:wordcamp-san-antonio.html</guid><category>wordpress</category><category>conference</category><category>san antonio</category></item><item><title>Security at Every Layer</title><link>http://blog.billhertzing.com/security-at-every-layer.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;Security at each pillar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2013 &lt;a href="http://www.rackspace.com/blog/pillars-of-cloudiness-no-5-security/"&gt;Wayne Walls counted down the five essential pillars of cloudiness&lt;/a&gt;.  These pillars are key considerations to keep in mind when building or running applications for the cloud.  Not too long ago this information was updated in a &lt;a href="http://www.rackspace.com/blog/explore-the-five-pillars-of-cloudiness/"&gt;published white paper on the topic&lt;/a&gt; and explores these pillars in greater detail.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this post is to touch on the security approaches that should be addressed at every layer.  One of the pillars mentioned is actually called Security.  It might seem circular in thinking as to how security can have security of its own, but I'll touch on that in that section.  In any case, I think you will find each pillar should probably carry its own security considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pillar 1: Parallel Computing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed and parallel computing is the idea of rather than running your application on a few pieces of infrastructure you spread them out to other systems.  You can leverage computational power by breaking them up by task.  Or, you can break them up by metrics such as job size, user platform or geo-location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However you do it, you will want to make sure that these systems are secure.  Making sure the worker servers (the ones doing the task) are only speaking to the message servers (the ones assigning the tasks) and nothing else.  This can be accomplished by having specific firewall and access controls for each system in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With parallel computing the idea is you have more than one path into your site.  This might be desktop version and a mobile version of your site.  Not just a plug-in that reads what browser you are using but a separate network path specifically designed and separate from other points of entry.  Keeping SSL certificates, for example, across all parallel paths is key to securing not only your but also proving your visitors with a safe and quality experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pillar 2: Modular Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modular Design means separating parts of an application into smaller pieces.  Similar to what was mentioned earlier, these smaller pieces should only talk to the systems they need to and ignore all the rest.  So, for example, if we are separating a caching mechanism from the application to its own server, it should only be allowed to receive traffic from the systems it supports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That way should something fail or become compromised, the chances of that activity impacting other elements of the infrastructure becomes reduced.  It also allows for easier troubleshooting should a problem arise.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security measures, however, that worked on one system may not be good enough in a modular environment.  Switching to a secure HTTPS rather than unsecure HTTP for your API requests is one illustration.  Where the requests were probably once contained in a single system, these requests might now have to traverse a public network or the Internet itself.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As network topology changes, going from private to hybrid or bursting into the cloud, make sure your security profiles changes with it.  A real simple example that could be overlooked is when using cloud load balancers.  When servers are deleted, make sure that the nodes are removed from the load balancer since it is common practice for those IP addresses to be reissued.  It would not be good for a person to visit a site and inadvertently arrive at another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pillar 3: Horizontal Scaling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike scaling vertically where you make systems larger, scaling horizontally means adding more systems.  With vertical scaling the security updates and patched software remains in place.  With horizontal scaling, new systems are brought online.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is absolutely important that these systems be brought up to speed before being put online.  New systems need not only content but also any security updates and patches.  Failure to do so can put your entire infrastructure at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pillar 4: Agility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When cloud traffic patterns change, being agile means your cloud needs to adapt.  Additional resources need to come online and then when no longer need be removed to keep costs in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being agile in terms of security is important as well.  With some systems security is managed at a server-by-server basis.  There are currently ways to be agile with the assistance of 3rd party SaaS tools.  These applications can act as a controller for firewalls, for example, making it easy to apply policies across multiple servers at once.  Additionally, some cloud providers offer the ability to pre-load public keys so as servers come online, they are applied accordingly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As good as these systems are they are still independent.  One system is not aware of what the other system is doing.  To add agility, these systems must be configured and designed to work in concert.  Configuration management is a good start for making sure systems meet set standards.  System discovery and automatic configuration are on the horizon that will help administrators be agile and secure at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pillar 5: Security in the Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;"Ultimately, security in the cloud is a shared responsibility between you and your cloud hosting provider." - Wayne Walls&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fundamental security aspect to consider.  What is the cloud provider bringing to the table?  What will I need to provide?  In the article mentioned at the beginning, Wayne talks about Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS), Platform-as-a-Service (PaaS) and Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) and the security requirements of each.  It's important to know what you are buying for your cloud application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security in the cloud is ultimately about people.  Here the fundamentals apply more than ever.  Strong password policies are a start.  Next is role-based access control then two-factor authentication.  Is this enough?  I am sure many of the recently publicized security breaches could be identified as a failure in security fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users getting around policy and walking away with data is a major concern.  One way to address this might be the issue of encryption keys.  My prediction is that employees of the future will be issued a personal key.  These keys will/should be kept on premise.  They should never be kept in the cloud.  This key will be used for the sending of emails and the securing/tracking of sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, naturally, is additional overhead.  To leverage the issuance of keys requires additional training, infrastructure and policies.  So, I imagine it will be a while before a balance is ever achieved between ease-of-use and security.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security can never be a set-it-and-forget-it matter.  It needs to be tracked, managed and change as your infrastructure changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have a comment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think? Did I miss anything?  Is any part unclear?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BillHertzing"&gt;Send me a message on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Hertzing</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.billhertzing.com,2015-01-21:security-at-every-layer.html</guid><category>security</category><category>cloud</category><category>five pillars</category></item><item><title>Use Your Data</title><link>http://blog.billhertzing.com/use-your-data.html</link><description>&lt;h2&gt;There's Data Everywhere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most companies don't think of themselves as a data company but they are.  Today sensors can be located in almost anything.  From shoes, televisions, computers, watches, phones, cars, refrigerators and more are all collecting or reporting data.  Then there's user data like what customers buy, how often, related items, and where they live can reveal a lot of information about who they are.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brand Company First.  Data Company Second.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most companies just want to sell a product or service.  While doing that, they collect information on their customers.  There's the first person data like usernames, passwords, gender, birthday and interests.  Then there is contextual data like where you live, what sporting events you attend, where you are located (Geodata) and what you buy.  Additionally, there is data through sensors.  Your phone probably has at least a motion sensor, GPS, light sensor and a microphone.   You get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tell me how it applies to my application.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give your customers relevant information that they can use to make informed choices.  Customers are saying, "I want this.  But, what do other think about this?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I purchased a hot air popcorn popper.   Not to make tasty, fluffy popcorn but to roast coffee beans.  As it turns out, you can purchase unroasted coffee beans; roast them for a few minutes in a popcorn popper.  And, after resting for about 12-24 hours later, have fresh roasted coffee at a fraction of the price.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in my buying process, I read reviews about how the popper was not so good at popping popcorn.  Some said it ran too hot while others said it threw the kernels out of the chamber.  For me, however, my interests were in how well it roasted coffee as reported by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to search other sources on the Internet to find out that, yes, this was a good popper for what I wanted to use it for.  One person even suggested that the company should re-brand the device as a coffee roaster as they could probably sell more units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Use the data you have for good or for awesome.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Good - Customer reviews and ratings.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having customer reviews and rating is pretty much standard for any site these days.  However, is anyone reading it other than other consumers?  Sometimes it feels like they are not.  Posts, comments and complaints go unanswered sometimes adding to the frustration.  Voice of the customer data is important.  They will tell you what is working and what isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Better - Help the customer understand your product as it applies to them and their situation.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I'm looking at a shirt, I'd like to know what it looks like on a guy similar to me.  Sure it looks great on the model but I'm not as tone as he is.  How long did the shirt last?  Did it fit well?  Was it too hot to wear in the summer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Best - Connect me with other people like me.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help me find other people around me who like the things I do.  Connect me with people who share the same interests as me or better yet, have been where I am and succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using your data to benefit your customers is something more companies should strive to accomplish.  When customers make more informed choices, there are fewer returns and refunds which directly impact the bottom line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have a comment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do you think? Did I miss anything?  Is any part unclear?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BillHertzing"&gt;Send me a message on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Hertzing</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 14:44:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.billhertzing.com,2015-01-12:use-your-data.html</guid><category>data</category><category>voc</category><category>coffee</category><category></category></item><item><title>Google Car on a Sunday Drive</title><link>http://blog.billhertzing.com/google-car.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://blogimages.billhertzing.com/sunday-drive.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can automated driving, like the Google Car really anticipate everything the road has to offer.   There are a lot of questions I have that need to be answered before getting into one and just letting it drive.  Just this weekend we visited my grandmother.  While driving I gave consideration too all the ways my transportation would change if I were in a Google Car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What happens when there is something in the road I want to avoid?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Car:&lt;/strong&gt; As I am driving along I might spot something I might want to avoid.  For example, one day we encountered a family of ducks crossing the road.   We have all seen it, the mama duck and her ducklings following behind her in single file.  People were already stopped in the on-coming lane and flashing their headlights and waving hands at us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only were we able to spot the ducks and slow down before they came into our lane, we were able to alert other motorists by turning on our flashers and sticking our hands out the window.  Mama and her followers were able to safely cross the road to the pond nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Car:&lt;/strong&gt; First, how would it know that there is trouble ahead?   Would traffic stopped in the on-coming lanes be any indication that trouble could be crossing into our lane?  Would the car be able to recognize something as small as a duck and determine that it needed to stop?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read that they have driven the roads of Mountain View, CA and have had driven them in an automated mode even with some chaos added.  They don't exactly say what that chaos is but I wonder if it included little ducks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What happens when there are emergency crews advising to exit?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Car:&lt;/strong&gt;  Sometimes driving down the highway, you have to detour to the access road.  This could be due to construction or an accident up ahead. Often you have to negotiate and cross multiple lanes of traffic in a short amount of time.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Car:&lt;/strong&gt; Would the car continue moving forward as it is following a digital map?  Can you override the course?  With no steering wheel or pedals as proposed by Google, how would you be able to turn around if you had to?   I would imagine you could control the car with an smart phone application. But, that would open up to a whole new level of complexities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What happens if traffic comes to a halt, how can I take an alternate route?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Car:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes on the way into work I'll take an alternate route.   This usually happens when traffic is at a complete standstill.  I'll find a parallel road three or so miles away and take it.  Knowing different routes into the office has helped save time and fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Car:&lt;/strong&gt; Again, with no steering wheel or pedals, how is an alternate route possible.  You could use your smart phone app and plot a different path to take.   Waze sort of does this.  However, the alternate routes are usually no better.  For example, they suggest getting off the freeway and taking the access road.  Which, as it turns out, is just as busy as the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do you do when you get behind somebody who is driving slow?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Car:&lt;/strong&gt;  In Texas, there is a tradition/courtesy that when you are driving slow, say on a two lane blacktop, you might drive on the shoulder to let others behind you pass when it is safe to do so.  Most of the time, however, people do not do this and will continue to drive 50 MPH in a 70 MPH zone.   When passing is allowed it is indicated on the road (usually as a broken yellow line) and, when safe, you can accelerate around the car continue on your way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Car:&lt;/strong&gt; Would the driver-less car just continue to drive at the speed of the car in front of it?  Sometimes going too slow is a safety hazard.  Can you pass using a self-driving car?  Would it know when it is safe to pass based on oncoming traffic?   Can it tell the difference from a no-passing zone and passing zone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do you do when somebody is driving unsafe?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Car: &lt;/strong&gt; Often people don't always drive in the safest manner.   They drift from lane to lane or cut in front of you at unexpected times.   One of the lessons I learned back in driver's education was "Leave yourself an out."  That means leave yourself space if you see a group of cars or give yourself distance if somebody is driving in an unsafe manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Car:&lt;/strong&gt; It's obvious the car has collision avoidance.  Many of those features are already advertised on TV for many of the more luxury brands.  Will an automated car know to avoid those drivers as they continue down the road?  Perhaps you could ID the car that is being driven poorly and know to keep clear of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of the questions that come to mind when people hail the coming of driver-less vehicles.  I believe they have their place for shuttles and delivery mechanisms.  They can also enable transportation for those who don't have a license to drive or are unable to drive.  However, with all the variables on and around the road, a full self-driving car for the masses is still way off in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1/5/2015 09:22 pm UPDATE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that at the Consumer Electronics Show or CES BMW has demonstrated a some of it's driver-less features. The feature that interests me most is the Automatic Valet.  That is a smart use of driver-less technology. &lt;a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/i-tried-and-failed-to-crash-a-bmw-i3-at-ces-2015/" title="Link to CNET"&gt;http://www.cnet.com/news/i-tried-and-failed-to-crash-a-bmw-i3-at-ces-2015/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Have a comment?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BillHertzing"&gt;Send me a message on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Bill Hertzing</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 22:58:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.billhertzing.com,2015-01-04:google-car.html</guid><category>Google</category><category>car</category><category>automation</category></item></channel></rss>